<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Over to you</title><link>https://overto.eu/</link><description>Recent content on Over to you</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-ie</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 03:41:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://overto.eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Programming languages</title><link>https://overto.eu/pages/languages/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 03:41:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/pages/languages/</guid><description>Ever since getting a Commodore 64 as a kid around 1990 and reading the user’s manual from cover to cover, I’ve always enjoyed programming, and learning new languages and concepts. Here’s some of the ones I’ve played with in more recent years.
Picat Picat is a really interesting language in the Prolog family, which adds imperative and convenience features like list comprehensions and mutable maps and arrays. It also includes a built-in constraint solver and SAT solver module, as well as support for calling out to external MIP and SMT solvers like Cbc and z3.</description></item><item><title>Gunzip into dd: don't forget `-c`</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/gunzip-into-dd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 03:28:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/gunzip-into-dd/</guid><description>Recently I was trying to copy the contents of one SD card to an identically-sized blank card, and ran into the problem of dd apparently stalling when writing to the new card, writing out zero records.
Here’s the command I used to read the first card:
sudo dd bs=4M if=/dev/sda1 status=progress|gzip &amp;gt; wee.img.gz Notice the use of gzip to compress the output coming out of dd. This is just to reduce the 90 GB or so of empty space on the card to (almost) nothing so my hard disk could hold the image.</description></item><item><title>Puzzle: Trauma Team bomb defusal #2</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/puzzle-trauma-team-bomb-defusal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 23:10:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/puzzle-trauma-team-bomb-defusal/</guid><description>One of my kids has gotten into the old Nintendo Wii game Trauma Team, part of the Trauma Center series by Atlus. It’s much easier and less action-oriented than the previous games — New Blood and Second Opinion, and more of a visual novel game for the most part, where the previous games involved quite difficult action-puzzling and strategy in real time.
There’s a section of the game where a series of bombs are placed, with puzzle hints left behind for disarming each bomb.</description></item><item><title>Nim: Outdated nimble.ini</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/nimble-outdated-ini/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 19:28:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/nimble-outdated-ini/</guid><description>I was interested today in trying to write a simple GUI program using Nim’s [nimx] library. But even with the latest Nim (2.0.0) and Nimble (0.14.2), I ran into this:
Reading official package list nimble.nim(683) getDownloadInfo Error: Package darwin@any version not found. This was confusing. I opened an issue on the nimx repo and the author pointed out that the darwin package is listed here, although I didn’t see it in this list.</description></item><item><title>Lenovo Ideapad 3 15ALC6 RAM upgrade: ignore the official docs</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/lenovo-ideapad-3-15alc6-ram/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 18:32:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/lenovo-ideapad-3-15alc6-ram/</guid><description>In late 2021 I picked up a Lenovo Ideapad 3 (15ALC6), a Ryzen 7 5700U-based laptop with 16GB RAM and a nice 1TB SSD. It was surprisingly cheap for what it offered, and after it went out of stock I tried to find another but it was either unobtainable or the price had gone way up.
Anyway, eventually I decided more RAM would be nice, since I was starting to hammer the SSD as swap.</description></item><item><title>Defold Android build issue: Problem parsing the package</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/defold-problem-parsing-package/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 01:59:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/defold-problem-parsing-package/</guid><description>While working on my first hobby gamedev project with Defold, I ran into an issue when trying to install the debug APK on my Android phone:
There was a problem parsing the package.
Searching the Defold forums and the web didn’t produce anything obviously relevant, so I looked at the sample project and tried to figure out what was different in the project settings. Most of the configuration was the same (that is to say, default), so I tried looking at the contents of the APK with unzip -l.</description></item><item><title>Rodland Intro Chords</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/rodland-intro-chords/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 04:32:59 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/rodland-intro-chords/</guid><description>I was watching cutscenes from the old arcade game &amp;#34;Rodland&amp;#34; and noticed a couple of chords with some nice voice leading.
I’m not sure I picked out all the notes, but here’s at least a partial transcription.</description></item><item><title>Benben</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/benben/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 22:41:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/benben/</guid><description>Today I was absolutely delighted to stumble upon a new command-line VGM (Video Game Music file) player called Benben. The author mentioned it in the Crystal programming language forum along with the underlying VGM playback library YunoSynth.
Benben is distributed as an executable AppImage file which worked perfectly out of the box on my Pop!_OS Linux system. Here’s a video of it playing the soundtrack to the PC-98 game &amp;#34;Rusty&amp;#34;:</description></item><item><title>BAM! and the history is gone</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/bam-history/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 06:27:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/bam-history/</guid><description>A few years ago I took this photo on Barrow Street near Ringsend, Dublin. BAM were tearing down some of the old Boland’s Mill site to make way for yet more shiny fancy corporate buildings. To be fair, they did repair some of the protected buildings which are part of the city’s heritage.
The graffiti quote is a pleasing reference to the catchphrase heard at the end of obnoxious &amp;#34;Cillit Bang&amp;#34; ads that used to run on UK and Irish TV:</description></item><item><title>Playing Revenant using Wine and Proton</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/revenant-wine-proton/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 02:11:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/revenant-wine-proton/</guid><description>TL;DR: I tried to run an old game called Revenant on Linux using both WINE and Proton, but both had problems. Here’s how I combined the powers of both to run the game on my Ubuntu machine.
Background The WINE project is an emulation layer that enables you to run a large amount of Windows programs on a Unix system. It can be difficult to configure, but it’s a fairly mature project that even supports some modern Windows games.</description></item><item><title>Learning</title><link>https://overto.eu/pages/learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 17:26:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/pages/learning/</guid><description>Experiences with tutorials, books or courses I’ve taken in recent times.
The Haskell book October 2017 — present
This is a very well-written book. But I found it hard to make progress quickly because some of the exercises were quite difficult and I felt compelled to complete them before moving on, although I think the author specifically advises to not get stuck on them and just move on if need be.</description></item><item><title>Living with dwm</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/dwm-extras/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 17:19:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/dwm-extras/</guid><description>You may have heard of tiling window managers like dwm or i3. These are pretty interesting from a nerdy elitist hacker perspective (&amp;#34;I know Unix!&amp;#34;), but can also look quite nice and make good use of on-screen space. I switched to dwm yesterday and enjoyed spending some time to figure out the absolute basics. On my old, small laptop though, I realised that it suits me best to just have a separate tag per application.</description></item><item><title>Software</title><link>https://overto.eu/pages/software/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 21:33:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/pages/software/</guid><description>Some software I’ve written and released as open-source:
Metron (source) — a minimal implementation of a metronome that allows you to only play the first of every n beats. Uses the HTML5 webaudio API to play clicks.
Pitcher (source) — a collection of exercises for training and testing absolute pitch (also known as perfect pitch). I trained with it for a while and didn’t make much progress, and took part in a research study in training absolute pitch via another method which was much more effective.</description></item><item><title>Jeff Schneider's Sick R&amp;B Chords</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/jeff-schneider-sick-rnb-chords/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 22:17:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/jeff-schneider-sick-rnb-chords/</guid><description>Jeff Schneider has some excellent instructive content on YouTube, and takes the time to explain some of the theory behind the music. Here, he plays a lush neo-soul chord progression, walks us through a nice tritone substitution and shows how we can use secondary dominants to introduce chords from outside the key.
Here’s a transcription, made much easier than usual thanks to Jeff’s animated keyboard.</description></item><item><title>Jazz chords from Paul Barton's "Piano Sounds Never Heard Before!"</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/barton-piano-sounds-chords/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 18:07:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/barton-piano-sounds-chords/</guid><description>There’s a really nice sequence of jazzy chords in Paul Barton’s YouTube video &amp;#34;Piano Sounds Never Heard Before!&amp;#34; at the 7:44 mark:
I really liked the chord progression and tried to transcribe it. You can find it here.</description></item></channel></rss>