<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>music on Over to you</title><link>https://overto.eu/tags/music/</link><description>Recent content in music on Over to you</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-ie</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 04:32:59 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://overto.eu/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rodland Intro Chords</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/rodland-intro-chords/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 04:32:59 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/rodland-intro-chords/</guid><description>I was watching cutscenes from the old arcade game &amp;#34;Rodland&amp;#34; and noticed a couple of chords with some nice voice leading.
I’m not sure I picked out all the notes, but here’s at least a partial transcription.</description></item><item><title>Benben</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/benben/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 22:41:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/benben/</guid><description>Today I was absolutely delighted to stumble upon a new command-line VGM (Video Game Music file) player called Benben. The author mentioned it in the Crystal programming language forum along with the underlying VGM playback library YunoSynth.
Benben is distributed as an executable AppImage file which worked perfectly out of the box on my Pop!_OS Linux system. Here’s a video of it playing the soundtrack to the PC-98 game &amp;#34;Rusty&amp;#34;:</description></item><item><title>Jeff Schneider's Sick R&amp;B Chords</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/jeff-schneider-sick-rnb-chords/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 22:17:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/jeff-schneider-sick-rnb-chords/</guid><description>Jeff Schneider has some excellent instructive content on YouTube, and takes the time to explain some of the theory behind the music. Here, he plays a lush neo-soul chord progression, walks us through a nice tritone substitution and shows how we can use secondary dominants to introduce chords from outside the key.
Here’s a transcription, made much easier than usual thanks to Jeff’s animated keyboard.</description></item><item><title>Jazz chords from Paul Barton's "Piano Sounds Never Heard Before!"</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/barton-piano-sounds-chords/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 18:07:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/barton-piano-sounds-chords/</guid><description>There’s a really nice sequence of jazzy chords in Paul Barton’s YouTube video &amp;#34;Piano Sounds Never Heard Before!&amp;#34; at the 7:44 mark:
I really liked the chord progression and tried to transcribe it. You can find it here.</description></item></channel></rss>