<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tech on Over to you</title><link>https://overto.eu/tags/tech/</link><description>Recent content in tech on Over to you</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-ie</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 03:28:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://overto.eu/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gunzip into dd: don't forget `-c`</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/gunzip-into-dd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 03:28:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/gunzip-into-dd/</guid><description>Recently I was trying to copy the contents of one SD card to an identically-sized blank card, and ran into the problem of dd apparently stalling when writing to the new card, writing out zero records.
Here’s the command I used to read the first card:
sudo dd bs=4M if=/dev/sda1 status=progress|gzip &amp;gt; wee.img.gz Notice the use of gzip to compress the output coming out of dd. This is just to reduce the 90 GB or so of empty space on the card to (almost) nothing so my hard disk could hold the image.</description></item><item><title>Puzzle: Trauma Team bomb defusal #2</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/puzzle-trauma-team-bomb-defusal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 23:10:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/puzzle-trauma-team-bomb-defusal/</guid><description>One of my kids has gotten into the old Nintendo Wii game Trauma Team, part of the Trauma Center series by Atlus. It’s much easier and less action-oriented than the previous games — New Blood and Second Opinion, and more of a visual novel game for the most part, where the previous games involved quite difficult action-puzzling and strategy in real time.
There’s a section of the game where a series of bombs are placed, with puzzle hints left behind for disarming each bomb.</description></item><item><title>Nim: Outdated nimble.ini</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/nimble-outdated-ini/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 19:28:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/nimble-outdated-ini/</guid><description>I was interested today in trying to write a simple GUI program using Nim’s [nimx] library. But even with the latest Nim (2.0.0) and Nimble (0.14.2), I ran into this:
Reading official package list nimble.nim(683) getDownloadInfo Error: Package darwin@any version not found. This was confusing. I opened an issue on the nimx repo and the author pointed out that the darwin package is listed here, although I didn’t see it in this list.</description></item><item><title>Lenovo Ideapad 3 15ALC6 RAM upgrade: ignore the official docs</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/lenovo-ideapad-3-15alc6-ram/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 18:32:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/lenovo-ideapad-3-15alc6-ram/</guid><description>In late 2021 I picked up a Lenovo Ideapad 3 (15ALC6), a Ryzen 7 5700U-based laptop with 16GB RAM and a nice 1TB SSD. It was surprisingly cheap for what it offered, and after it went out of stock I tried to find another but it was either unobtainable or the price had gone way up.
Anyway, eventually I decided more RAM would be nice, since I was starting to hammer the SSD as swap.</description></item><item><title>Playing Revenant using Wine and Proton</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/revenant-wine-proton/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 02:11:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/revenant-wine-proton/</guid><description>TL;DR: I tried to run an old game called Revenant on Linux using both WINE and Proton, but both had problems. Here’s how I combined the powers of both to run the game on my Ubuntu machine.
Background The WINE project is an emulation layer that enables you to run a large amount of Windows programs on a Unix system. It can be difficult to configure, but it’s a fairly mature project that even supports some modern Windows games.</description></item><item><title>Living with dwm</title><link>https://overto.eu/posts/dwm-extras/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 17:19:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/posts/dwm-extras/</guid><description>You may have heard of tiling window managers like dwm or i3. These are pretty interesting from a nerdy elitist hacker perspective (&amp;#34;I know Unix!&amp;#34;), but can also look quite nice and make good use of on-screen space. I switched to dwm yesterday and enjoyed spending some time to figure out the absolute basics. On my old, small laptop though, I realised that it suits me best to just have a separate tag per application.</description></item></channel></rss>