<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Over to you</title><link>https://overto.eu/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Over to you</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-ie</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 09:19:19 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://overto.eu/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://overto.eu/pages/about-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 09:19:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/pages/about-me/</guid><description>Howye! I’m Oisín, a programmer and musician living in Dublin, Ireland. Here’s a few of the things I’m into and may occasionally write something about here:
Programming in a bajillion different languages, for fun and (once upon a time) profit
Music in many flavours, from jazz to traditional Irish tunes and old computer game soundtracks. From time to time I’ll post transcriptions of music that catches my fancy.
Complaining about things.</description></item><item><title>Startups</title><link>https://overto.eu/pages/startups/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:23:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/pages/startups/</guid><description>Startups I’ve founded or co-founded with others.
Digifeye / Style-Eyes (2012-2016) Problem: Finding the right clothes can be hard.
Answer: An app that lets the user take photos of an item of clothing (whether from a magazine, online or in the real world) and used computer vision to find visually similar products.
Business model: Initially, affiliate commission from product sales. Later, we had talks about a B2B offering, embedding the technology on retailers&amp;#39; websites, but it didn’t pan out.</description></item><item><title>Programming languages</title><link>https://overto.eu/pages/languages/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 03:41:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/pages/languages/</guid><description>Ever since getting a Commodore 64 as a kid around 1990 and reading the user’s manual from cover to cover, I’ve always enjoyed programming, and learning new languages and concepts. Here’s some of the ones I’ve played with in more recent years.
Contents Picat Picat and SAT/CP solving Optimal plan search with Picat’s planner Other Picat programs and libraries Nim Nim programs Haskell Haskell programs Ur/web Ur/web programs / utilities Picat Picat is a really interesting language in the Prolog family, which adds imperative and convenience features like list comprehensions and mutable maps and arrays.</description></item><item><title>Learning</title><link>https://overto.eu/pages/learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 17:26:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/pages/learning/</guid><description>Experiences with tutorials, books or courses I’ve taken in recent times.
The Haskell book October 2017 — present
This is a very well-written book. But I found it hard to make progress quickly because some of the exercises were quite difficult and I felt compelled to complete them before moving on, although I think the author specifically advises to not get stuck on them and just move on if need be.</description></item><item><title>Software</title><link>https://overto.eu/pages/software/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 21:33:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/pages/software/</guid><description>Some software I’ve written and released as open-source:
Nimplication — a toy SAT solver using the DPLL algorithm (and maybe CDCL in future).
vfconcat — generate videos from PNG frames with inconsistent durations. Timings are recovered from the difference in consecutive frame timestamps, producing a control file for ffmpeg.
Metron (source) — a minimal implementation of a metronome that allows you to only play the first of every n beats.</description></item></channel></rss>