<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Over to you</title><link>https://overto.eu/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Over to you</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-ie</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 03:41:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://overto.eu/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Programming languages</title><link>https://overto.eu/pages/languages/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 03:41:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/pages/languages/</guid><description>Ever since getting a Commodore 64 as a kid around 1990 and reading the user’s manual from cover to cover, I’ve always enjoyed programming, and learning new languages and concepts. Here’s some of the ones I’ve played with in more recent years.
Picat Picat is a really interesting language in the Prolog family, which adds imperative and convenience features like list comprehensions and mutable maps and arrays. It also includes a built-in constraint solver and SAT solver module, as well as support for calling out to external MIP and SMT solvers like Cbc and z3.</description></item><item><title>Learning</title><link>https://overto.eu/pages/learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 17:26:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/pages/learning/</guid><description>Experiences with tutorials, books or courses I’ve taken in recent times.
The Haskell book October 2017 — present
This is a very well-written book. But I found it hard to make progress quickly because some of the exercises were quite difficult and I felt compelled to complete them before moving on, although I think the author specifically advises to not get stuck on them and just move on if need be.</description></item><item><title>Software</title><link>https://overto.eu/pages/software/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 21:33:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://overto.eu/pages/software/</guid><description>Some software I’ve written and released as open-source:
Metron (source) — a minimal implementation of a metronome that allows you to only play the first of every n beats. Uses the HTML5 webaudio API to play clicks.
Pitcher (source) — a collection of exercises for training and testing absolute pitch (also known as perfect pitch). I trained with it for a while and didn’t make much progress, and took part in a research study in training absolute pitch via another method which was much more effective.</description></item></channel></rss>